PURVA DESHPANDE (M.Pth Neurosciences)

dpurva5@gmail.com

Sector 143 (+91) 8698396001 Noida, UP 201305

https://www.linkedin.com/in/purva-deshpande-51a350178

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A highly motivated individual with effective communication skills to understand patients and guide care givers. Excellent ability to work closely with other health professionals. Experience in multiple fields of physiotherapy, especially in adult and pediatric neurological rehabilitation

Neurosciences

• Basic life support instructor

Pediatrics

Yoga Instructor

• Clinic management

• Therapeutic Taping

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS DEMONSTRATED

Mission Walk Rehabilitation Center

November 2022 – April 2023

Full time Physiotherapist and consultant Neuro physiotherapist at Mission Walk

Treated and assisted various neurological conditions in adult & pediatric population using advanced intervention techniques

Clinical Experience

March 2020 – November 2021

Completed 1500+ hours of clinical practice at Dr. Maneesha Deshpande's physiotherapy clinic in Nagpur

- Treated musculoskeletal and neurological conditions using advanced intervention techniques
- Learnt clinic management techniques and single-handedly managed the facility on various occasions

OPD experience/Resident Doctor

November 2019 – November 2021

Completed 2000+ hours of OPD practice primarily tending to pediatrics children with minimal supervision

- Treated pediatric children as well as adults in outpatient department and inpatient department
- Treated patients with COVID-19 in May 2021
- Conducted a project on Down's syndrome children of age 6-18 years
- Conducted basic life support training program for residents in Aurangabad

Conducted multiple sessions on practicing yoga and its benefits

June 2018 – April 2023

EDUCATION

Yoga Instructor

M.Pth (April 2022): VSPM College of Physiotherapy, Nagpur specialized in Neurosciences

B.Pth (August 2018): MGM School of Physiotherapy, Aurangabad

Diploma in Yoga (May 2018): Yashwantrao Chawan Open University, Nashik

PROFESSIONAL ASSOCIATIONS

Registered Physiotherapist at Maharashtra Council of Occupational Therapy and Physiotherapy, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India (Since 2019)

CONFERENCES AND WORKSHOPS

- 1. Multidisciplinary Healthcare Conference AIIMS Delhi 2016
- 2. Therapeutic Taping Basic 2017
- 3. Musculofascial Release Therapy 2019
- 4. Principles and practice of asana 2021

- 5. Fall prevention in elderly rehabilitation perspective 2020
- 6. Basic research methodology workshop 2020
- 7. Online certificate course on down syndrome 2022

OTHER RELEVANT INFORMATION

Languages: English, Hindi, Marathi

Computer skills: MS Excel, MS Word, MS PowerPoint